《越狱》第四季 第十九集
Prison.Break.S04E19
《越狱》剧情回顾
Previously on Prison Break.
这是简单介绍
This is an overview.
这只是一切的开始
That's just the beginning of what's on here.
你履行了你的诺言
You honor your side of the agreement,
我会在明天的会上说明一切
And I will do the unveiling at the conference tomorrow.
我以为我们是和这些人合作
I thought we were working with these people.
我也这么想
So did I.
为了这些东西
Damn well almost got
我们差点连命都没了
Our asses handed to us getting these.
这些是明天要用的
These things are for tomorrow.
我今天就要"锡拉"
I want Scylla today!
文森特・圣丁斯奇
Vincent Sandinsky.
-有事吗  -跟我走
- Yes?  - Let's go.
你想要干什么
What are you going to do?
我警告过你别来  迈克
I warned you not to come, Michael.
从大局上看  一切都还没结束
Well, it's not over, not by a long shot.
克里斯蒂娜・罗斯・斯科菲尔德
Christina Rose Scofield,
你听过这个名字吗
That name mean anything to you?
没有
No.
喂
Yes.
妈妈  你很想打败他吗
How badly do you want him, mom?
迈克  听我说
Michael, listen to me.
这不是我要的答案
That's not an answer.
我会再联系你的
I'll be in touch.
我被打的连命都没了
I get the ass-kicking of a lifetime
你们却空着手回来了
And you come back empty-handed?
-什么  -林肯和迈克的妈妈
- What?  - Linc and Michael's mother
手上有"锡拉"
She's got Scylla
在迈阿密
Here in Miami.
准备飞机
Fuel the jet.
我们去迈阿密
We're going to Miami.
他肯定知道点事情
The guy knows something.
我知道我帮不了你们
I don't know what else I can do to help you guys.
求你们放了我吧
Please let me go.
我不会告诉任何人的
I won't say a word to anyone about this.
没听说过克里斯蒂娜・斯科菲尔德吗
Never heard of the name Christina Scofield?
我说了  没有
I told you, no.
真的
Never?
Never.
说
Yeah.
你在机场劫走的那个人
That guy you picked up at the airport.
有些事情你必须了解
There's something you should know.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
他不是一个无关的人  林肯
He's not some innocent victim, Linc.
他和克里斯蒂娜一直互通邮件
He and Christina have been exchanging e-mails,
电话  等等等等
Phone calls, you name it.
他们肯定是计划好了
They've got some kind of plan.
但是  我还不知道是什么
I just haven't figured it out yet.
-谢谢  -那你想怎么对付他
- Thanks.  - So what are you going to do with him, Linc?
离开这里  迈克
Leave town, Michael.
林肯
Linc?
"锡拉"在什么地方
Where's Scylla?
我不知道
No.
"锡拉"在什么地方
Where's Scylla?!
你准备好了吗
You ready?
-快了  那是圣丁斯奇的电话吗  -是的
- Almost.Is that Sandinsky's phone?  - Yeah.
祝你好运
Good luck.
谢谢  我可能是需要点运气
Thanks, I may need it.
又是迈克打来的
It's Michael again
用的是圣丁斯奇的电话
On Sandinsky's phone.
我以为他把电话关了
I thought he turned it off.
现在是开着的  追踪信号
Well, now it's on. Track it.
迈克
Michael?
喂  克里斯蒂娜
Hello, Christina.
我希望 你对我说实话
I hope you're ready to talk.
我们从文森特・圣丁斯奇说起
Let's start with Vincent Sandinsky.
文森特・圣丁斯奇  那个科学家吗
Vincent Sandinsky the scientist?
他是我的老朋友
He, uh, he's an old friend of mine.
有点让人讨厌  你觉得呢
A bit of a bore, don't you think?
但谁管他呢
But who cares about him?
我更想谈谈你的问题
I'd rather talk about you.
我想和你面对面谈
I'd rather meet you face-to-face.
除非你把"锡拉"带来  否则免谈
Unless you're bringing me Scylla, I'm not interested.
没有"锡拉"  就别想见面
No Scylla, no meeting.
这是我唯一的条件
That's all I can offer.
你的目标是什么
What do you hope to accomplish?
十分钟内给我答案
I need your answer in ten minutes,
那将是我最后一次给你打电话
And that's the last time i'm calling back.
找到他了
And found him.
他在埃尔波特尔的工业区
He's in an industrial park in El Portal.
就在海边
Right up the coast.
很好
All right,
我们行动
Let's go.
你撒谎  你撒谎
You're lying, you're lying.
我不是公司的人
I don't work for the company,
你就是谎话连篇
Six words that never prove true.
你玩完了  认命吧
Come on, man, this is over, look around!
你还想耍什么把戏
What are you doing here?!
我发誓什么都不知道
I swear I don't know anything, I do.
他说的我一点都不知道
I don't know what he's talking about.
我是来开会的
I am here for a conference,
就这么多  我不知道其他人说了什么
That's all, I don't know who told you otherwise.
我知道了
I do,
迈克也一句实话没说
And Michael's also full of crap.
-他没理由撒谎  -事实上  他有
- He's got no reason to lie.  - Actually, he does.
迈克给我们假情报  就能找机会插手
Michael's leading us off the scent, so he can get in...
他和我们一样
He doesn't want Christina to have Scylla
不想让克里斯蒂娜得到"锡拉"
Any more than we do.
他对我们撒谎  不是一两次了
It's not the first time he's lied to us.
"锡拉"在什么地方
Where is it?
-林肯  -算了  林肯
- Linc.  - Come on, Linc,
他要是死了  线索就断了
He can't talk if he's dead.
-最后三秒钟  -别开枪
- You got three seconds. - No!
布鲁斯
Burrows!
把枪放下
Put the gun down.
我要和文森特谈谈
Vincent and I need to talk.
文森特
Vincent?
我们有协议的
We had a deal.
新的协议
New deal.
我来负责
I'm taking charge.
文森特和我是老朋友
Vincent and I are old friends.
你们在哪里找到他的
Where'd you find him?
在飞机跑道上
At an airstrip.
他知道一些"锡拉"的事情
He's got something to do with Scylla.
很好
Good.
那么你可以帮我找到"锡拉"了
Then you can help me find it,
对吗  文森特
Can't you, Vincent?
而且你能帮我找到克里斯蒂娜・斯科菲尔德
And you can help me find Christina Scofield.
圣丁斯奇博士作为
Dr. Sandinsky has been
公司的特工已经
A company operative since
多久了  文森特
How long's it been, Vincent?
21年了
21 years.
已经21年了
21 years of service.
科学家  统计学家
Scientist, statistician,
职业士兵
Expert field combatant.
你为什么来迈阿密
What brought you to Miami?
想起来了吗
Does that help?
她请我来的
She invited me, okay?
She invited me.
-谁  -克里斯蒂娜・斯科菲尔德
- Who?  - Christina Scofield.
我为她工作
I'm working with her.
这样你就明白来龙去脉了吧  布鲁斯
That brings you full circle, doesn't it,Burrows?
但是  你早就知道了
But you knew that already.
你准备什么时候告诉我
When were you planning on
你妈妈是幕后主使
Telling me that your mother was behind all this?
我们也是刚刚知道
We just found out.
但是  最起码  你知道
But bottom line is, you knew.
你们都知道
All of you!
跪下
On your knees.
你们听见了  跪下
You heard him, get down.
你不用
Oh, not you.
我不想和没有能力的人
I don't need to make deals
做任何交易
With men who can't do their jobs.
如果巴格韦尔是唯一一个有能力的人
If Bagwell is the only one who is competent here,
他一个人就能解决
He'll do it alone.
什么  你说什么
What?! Are you serious?!
你以为是谁找到这个人的
Who do you think found this guy?!
"锡拉"在哪里
Where's Scylla?
我不知道
I don't know.
I don't.
她没告诉我她放在哪里
She doesn't tell me where she keeps it,
但是  我知道她住哪
But I do know where she's staying.
水塔饭店  1099房间
A place called edgewater tower, room 1099.
你只剩下今天
You have today.
就一天了
One day.
不要浪费时间了  布鲁斯
You're wasting time, Burrows.
一天
One day.
是你告的密
You tipped him off.
巴格韦尔  你回来
No, Bagwell.
你呆在这里
You stay here.
对  蒂博格
Yeah, Theodore.
他更需要你
He needs you.
你最好离我们都远点
But you'd better stay away from us.
这就是迈克打电话的地方
This is where Michael's signal is coming from?
-是的  -太好了
- Yeah.  - Perfect.
小心
Be careful.
呆在这儿
Stay here.
检查一下
Check it out.
快点
Let's go.
Let's go!
他要跑
He's leaving.
快点  他跑不了多远
Come on, he can't be that far away.
追上他
Let's go.
快出去
Out.
跟我走吧
Let's go.
好了
All right.
"锡拉"在哪里
Where is it?
你知道我不会说的  对不对
You don't really expect me to answer that, do you?
实际上  你会说
Actually, I do,
不说你就死命一条
Because your life depends on it,
根据你的记录
And considering your track record,
我可以很保守地估计
I think it's safe to assume
你总是为自己着想
That you're always looking out for number one.
迈克  这一天我等了25年了
I've waited 25 years for this moment, Michael.
我不可能把我知道的全告诉你
There's no way I can say everything I want to say.
我为什么要让你说
Why should I let you?
因为我是你的母亲
Because I'm your mother.
有些事情是改变不了的
That's something you can't change.
是忘不掉的
It's something you can't take away.
很高兴见到你  莎拉
It's nice to meet you, Sara.
迈克能认识你
In some ways, Michael's done very well
是他福气好
For himself.
至于其他  我就不敢那么说了
In other ways, i'm not so sure.
林肯让你走了一条艰难的路
Lincoln has led you down a dark path.
我自己决定的
I make my own decisions.
你帮林肯逃出监狱
You break Lincoln out of prison
他却帮克兰兹将军做事
And he goes to work for general Krantz.
他有他自己的理由
And he has his reasons.
如果你想找我们之间的共同点
But if you're looking for some kind of common ground
我觉得就那么多了
Between us, maybe that's it.
我也不想让林肯给公司卖命
I don't want to see Lincoln working for the company, either.
最少你不再给他找借口了
At least you've stopped making excuses for him.
我只是不再用主观考虑问题
I stopped making judgments.
我已经不能那么做了
Something I couldn't afford.
这些都是以前的问题了
But that was a long time ago,
这不是我们谈话的主题
And that's not why we're here.
我知道
No.
你是对的
You're right.
我们都不想公司得到"锡拉"
None of us wants to see Scylla go back to the company.
如果我们能摒弃前嫌
So, if we can put the past behind us,
我们还是可以做到的
Maybe we can work something out.
举个例子
Like what?
做个交易
Like a deal.
交易
"A deal"?
好吧
All right,
你告诉我"锡拉"在哪
You tell me where Scylla is,
我们再讨论细节
And we'll work out the details later.
我们五五分
We'll go 50-50.
母子行动
A mother-son operation?
可能
Maybe.
首先  "锡拉"
But first, Scylla.
算了吧  迈克  我更了解
Please, Michael, I know better.
我们是一类人
We're very similar.
我知道  当我们看着一个事物
I know what it's like to look at the big picture,
想到的却是所有小的零件
See all the little moving parts...
手术之后大脑更灵活了
How much easier it is to think after the surgery.
我了解你
I know you.
这就是为什么你不可能
That's why you'll never be able to manipulate me
像操纵其他人一样操纵我
Like you do the rest of the world.
你没时间了
You're running out of time.
里面没人
All right, there's no one back here!
他们刚刚还在
Well, they were here, but of course,
但是现在肯定没人
There's nobody here now.
总是这样
'Cause that's what happens.
你们说呢
You know, this
所有的事情
Whole thing...
全部都是
It's just...
全部都是垃圾
It's just... crap!
我们总是比别人慢一步
We're always one move behind,
每次都是这样
Every step of the way.
而且巴格韦尔现在小人得志
Yeah, and it's just going to get worse now that
更让我们觉得难受
Bagwell is breathing down our backs.
你怎么能犯那种错误
How do you make that kind of mistake, huh?!
让那个垃圾和我们在一起
And let that inbred get anywhere near us.
不  我们就不该为克兰兹做事
No, no, no, the first mistake was working for Krantz.
对  那是第一个错误
Okay, that was the first mistake.
那你觉得以后会怎么样
what do you think's going to happen now
他和他的狐朋狗友作威作福
that he's in town and he has his goons
我们现在怎么办
Calling the shots? what's going to happen now?
我在这些事情发生前
Yeah, I should've known better
就应该想到的
Than to get anywhere near this.
好了  我们该走了
All right, you know what? we should go.
-我们走吧  -我们不能走
- Let's go.  - No, we can't go,
你看过那些照片了
Because you saw the photos,right?
所以你应该知道
You saw the photos, so you know
他会对他们做什么
what he's going to do with them.
我们早该知道他会对他们做什么了
We should have known what he was going to do with them!
我们应该早就知道
That's what we should've...
冷静下来
Hey, hey, hey! just calm down.
说实话吧  交易吹了
You know what, the deal is over.
你知我知
Okay? you know it, i know it.
所有人都知道  我们永远也逃不掉了
Everybody knows it. we're not getting out of here!
要不我们自己走向绞刑架
We're going to take a walk right to the gallows,
要不就是其他人把我们干掉
Or somebody else is going to stab us in the back!
我以前也遇到过  但我活下来了
I did that walk and I survived.
就算我们赢了
Even if we win,
我们就真的赢了吗
Do we win?
你也不信的  对吧
You don't believe that, do you?
我会去做该做的
Look, i'm going to do what i got to do.
你要不想和我一起  随你
If you don't want to roll with me, that's fine.
这是什么
What is that?
租借收据  银色小货车
Rental receipt, a silver minivan.
这是什么
What is this?
你对这个了解多少
What do you know about this?
我们在小古巴
We found a whole
发现了一箱子这个
Box of them down in Little Cuba.
还有很多枪
Guns, too.
你对这个了解多少
What do you know about this?
她想让我在那儿演讲
She wanted me to speak there.
是关于锡拉吗
About Scylla?
她说会提前给我讲稿
She said she'd give me the script beforehand,
我只知道这个
that's all I know.
她说只是纯粹对科学感兴趣
She said her interest was purely scientific.
她的兴趣是财富
Her interest was financial.
一年前她找到我  说了自己的想法
She came to me about a year ago with an idea.
她并不想利用锡拉作为永久的基石
Rather than build our organization
来巩固我们的组织
With Scylla as the permanent cornerstone,
而是想利用这项发明
She wanted to use the technology
赚取短期利润
To make a quick profit.
如果发生了什么
If certain events occurred,
很多国家会觉得
Various nations might feel the need
这种现代防御系统很有必要
For a more modern defense system,
他们就会问我们要
And they'd come to us for the answers.
太阳能武器
Solar weaponry.
水去盐技术
Water desalination.
现在告诉我们吧
Now, what do you know about all this?
知道的我都说了
I told you all I know.
这主意太疯狂了
Well, I thought it was a crazy idea.
外行人的计划
Plan of an amateur.
但我猜她会火冒三丈
But I figured she'd be angry.
她没资格持有卡
She wasn't allowed to hold a card.
你想说什么
Now, what was that?
远不止这些
I think it's more than that.
是嘛
Really?
她告诉你什么了
What did she tell you?
我知道公司运作的方式
I know how the company operates.
像艾克菲尔德那样的假公司
Shell corporations like Ecofield,
大量的经费滥用
Rampant misuse of funds.
你的确是坐在金矿上
You're literally sitting on a gold mine.
但你的领导
But your leadership
只利于你和你朋友
Only benefits you and your friends
及今后十代的发展
Ten generations in the future.
而你
And you
希望看到公司从内部瓦解
Would like to see the company implode?
我希望看到改观
I want to see something happen.
你简直是鼠目寸光
You think too small.
老挝
Laos?
得利前  我们都会没命
We'll all be dead before that pays off.
老挝指什么
Uh, "Laos," sir?
你不必多问
Don't trouble yourself.
布鲁斯
Burrows?
我有个问题问你的朋友
I got a question for your friend.
什么问题
What is it?
问他DMB是什么意思
Ask him what the letters "DMB" mean.
DMB对你  有什么特殊含义吗
Do the letters "DMB" mean anything to you?
真遗憾
I'm sorry.
我以为你有点眼色的
I thought you understood me.
她说东西放在
She said her place was
戴德迈阿密银行那儿
On the same block as Dade-Miami bank.
听到了吗
Did you hear that?
知道了
I got it.
他最好说的是实话
He'd better be telling the truth.
看教授还知道什么
See what else the doctor knows.
-不要啊  -克里斯蒂娜的计划是什么
- No... - What's Christina's plan?!
我不知道
I don't know.
不知道
也许我们应该
Maybe we should've...
也许我们应该跟踪她什么的
Maybe we should've followed her or something.
坐下
Sit down for me.please.
我和她谈谈如何
How about I talk to her?
也许我有不同的理解
I might have some perspective.
毕竟我妈妈没有在我6岁时丢下我
She didn't leave me when I was six.
好的
Okay.
莎拉  很遗憾我们以这种方式见面
I'm sorry we had to meet this way, Sara.
我很遗憾我们竟然会见面
I'm sorry we had to meet at all.
迈克在去年经受了
Michael's been through a lot in
太多痛苦
the last year at some point.
他已经不堪重负
It's going to be too much for him.
迈克可以处理好的
Michael can handle it.
他习惯于充满变化的生活
He's never known a life without change.
你说得好像很了解他一样
Oh, you say that like you know him.
没错
Oh, I do.
比你了解多了
Better than you.
这不太可能吧
I don't see how that's possible.
你生下孩子时就知道了
Well, you will when your child's born.
起初我并不确定
See, I wasn't sure at first,
但你脸色不好
But you do have that drawn look.
而且我看到你面对危险时
And I see the way you protect yourself
保护自己的方式
when you sense danger.
你自己察觉不到  这是本能
You don't even know you're doing it. It's instinct.
你对母性本能了解多少
And what is it you know about maternal instinct?
我尝试当个好母亲
I've tried to be a mother.
甚至是对于林肯
Even to Lincoln.
你怎么好意思说
How can you say that?
你一句话不说就抛下他们
You left them without so much as an explanation.
但如果迈克听...
But if Michael would listen...
知道吗  你可以停手了
You know what? you can stop.
你没资格为自己的行为辩解
You can't justify what you did.
迈克不知道你怀孕了
Michael doesn't know you're pregnant,
对吧
Does he?
怎么了
What happened?
她什么都没说
Uh... I got nothing.
你好  乔伊丝
Hello, Joyce.
你好  我叫当・赛尔夫
How are you? my name is Don Self,
是国土安全局的
Homeland Security.
别担心  没什么事
Don't worry, there's nothing the matter.
我只是帮朋友一个忙
I'm just here doing a favor for my friend.
他妈妈昨天去世了
See, his mother passed away yesterday.
她最后的愿望和遗嘱
Okay, and her last will and testament
放在你们这儿一个安全箱中
Is in one of your security boxes.
是6468号
It's actually box 6468.
有许可吗
Is he authorized to access it?
这就是问题了  他没有
See, that's the problem. he's not.
但我们可以填写单据
But we're willing to fill out all the paperwork...
抱歉  只有获得许可的个人
I'm sorry. only authorized individuals
才能够取得安全箱
Are allowed to access safe deposit...
女士  我必须拿到那箱子
Listen, lady, I need to get in that box.
你们老板在哪
Where's your boss?
先生  有什么要帮忙的吗
Sir? sir, can I help you?
我要拿到我妈妈的安全箱
Yeah.I need to get in my mom's safe deposit box.
-你有法院命令吗  -没有
- Do you have a court order?  - No. no.
DMB政策不允许任何人...
DMB policy prevents anyone...
这就是政策
Here's the policy.
我要开6468号箱子  就现在
Okay, I need to open box 6468. Right now.
我是当・赛尔夫  国土安全局的
Name's Don Self, Homeland Security.
打扰了  弗兰克先生
Excuse me,Mr. Frank?
6468号一分钟前刚被人取走
Number 6468 was accessed a minute ago.
他刚离开
He just left.
是一个带着银色手提箱的男的
It was the guy with the silver suitcase.
他在那里
There he is.
看起来像是大使馆里的那个
Hey, that looks like the guy from the embassy.
班纳吉先生  你好吗
Mr. Banerjee, how are you?
我试着联系克里斯蒂娜・汉普顿
I'm trying to reach Christina Hampton.
她现在正在开会
She's in a meeting right now.
五点前无法联系上
I don't talk to her before five.
交易就取消
The deal is off.
听好
Okay.
这是我的最后提议
This is my final offer.
你带我找到"锡拉"
You're going to take me to Scylla,
就可以走了
And then you can walk.
没有质问
No questions.
也没人去告诉将军
No one tells the General.
你下半辈子可以安稳生活
You can live the rest of your life
就像这一切没有发生过
Like this never happened,
但是"锡拉"是我的
But Scylla is mine.
林肯绝不会放手不管的
Lincoln would never let that happen.
他没必要知道
He doesn't have to know.
你们小时候就总是不合
Even as children, you couldn't agree.
你们常常争吵
You fought about everything.
你们俩太不一样了
The two of you couldn't be more different.
但你知道的  是吧  迈克
But you know that, don't you, Michael?
这不关林肯的事
This isn't about Lincoln.
你的眼睛是蓝色的  而他是绿色的
You have blue eyes, he has green.
他去玩卡车
He played with trucks.
而你把电视机给拆了
You took apart the television set.
我没必要指出
And I don't need to point out
你们的智商
The difference in IQ
或者是性情的区别
Or temperament.
你知道我在说什么
You know what I'm getting at,
是吧  迈克
Don't you, Michael?
我不知道
I don't have any idea
你在说什么
What you're talking about.
心底里你其实一直都知道
You've always known it deep in your heart.
只是没人能来证实
You just had no one to confirm it.
林肯
Lincoln...
不是你的亲生哥哥
...Isn't your brother.
这是真的
It's true.
我应该早点告诉你
I should have told you before,
但你一直很敬仰他
But you always looked up to him, and
我没想到事情会发展到这个地步
I had no idea things would happen like this.
你不知道你在说什么
You don't know what you're saying.
你有见过
Have you ever
林肯婴儿时候的相片吗
Seen pictures of Lincoln as a baby?
-当然  -没有
- Yes. - No.
根本就没有
There aren't any.
他3岁时你父亲收养了他
Your father didn't adopt him until he was three years old.
他父母为公司效力
His parents worked for the company.
他们在马尼拉的一次爆炸中丧生
They were killed in an explosion in Manila.
奥尔多第二天把他带回家
Aldo brought him home the next day.
他觉得那是他的责任
He felt it was his duty.
却无视我的感受
He didn't ask me how I felt.
我和他之间从未有过
I...I never bonded with him
母子之间的感情
Like mother and son.
所以他总是很气愤
He was always so angry.
就算可以理解
Understandably so...
但他还是太小  记不清他的亲生母亲
He was too young to remember his mother, but
可他一直都知道少了什么东西
He always knew something was missing.
可恶  你竟然用这一招
I can't believe you're playing this card.
对不起  迈克
I'm sorry, Michael.
但我对你的感觉是不同的
But I felt differently about you.
你能体会到
And you could tell.
所以你才一直有内疚感
That's why you always felt guilty.
所以你总在林肯必死无疑时
Why you were always throwing yourself over the cliff
奋不顾身  前来救他
After Lincoln was already dead at the bottom.
所以你才进了监狱  毁了原来的生活
It's why you went to prison and pissed your life away.
你不会明白为什么
You don't know why I did
我会做这些
The things I did!
你根本就不在我身边
You weren't there!
天知道你本该有多大的成就
Who knows what you could have accomplished.
可你一直觉得必须收敛自己的锋芒
But you always felt like you had to make less of yourself
才不至于让林肯太可悲
To make Lincoln look less pathetic in comparison.
林肯胜过亲兄
Lincoln was more of a brother to me
而你枉为人母
than you were ever a mother.
你抛弃了我
You left.
他陪伴着我
He stayed.
他供养我
He fed me.
让我不至于颠沛流离
Kept me off the streets.
供我读书
Put me through school.
怎么做到的
How?
让你不停的陷入麻烦吗
By getting in trouble over and over again,
就像他现在那样
Just like he is right now.
现在是什么意思
What do you mean, right now?
他在哪
Where is he?
他在路上
He's out
去找"锡拉"  但他是不会找到的
Looking for Scylla, and he's not going to find it.
也许你该打电话告诉他
Maybe you should call him and tell him.
除非你们之间
Unless there's too much
感情很差
Bad blood between you.
或根本毫无感情
Or no blood.
谁打过来的
Who's the guy in the ring?
是迈克吗
Is it Michael?
他会没事的  别紧张
He's gonna be all right. Just relax.
他在哪
Where is he?
快跟上他  快
All right, keep up with him, come on.
我正在做  少罗嗦
I am. Just shut up.
不是我不想帮你
It's not that I don't want to help you.
只是我不愿再看见你为了他牺牲自己
It's just that I hate to see you go running after him again.
迈克  别这样
Michael. Come here!
-迈克  -他在哪
- Michael! - Where is he?
好吧  你想为了他
Okay. You want to go running after him,
把自己的生活一次性毁掉  就动手吧
Flush your life down the toilet once and for all? Go ahead!
我发誓
I swear!
如果你不告诉我他在哪
If don't you tell me where he is,
我发誓就亲手杀了你
Or I'll kill you,myself, I swear to God!
我会亲手杀了你
I'll kill you myself.
迈克
Michael!
快告诉我
Come on! Tell me!
他在哪  他在哪
Where is he? where is he?
林肯在哪
Where is Lincoln?
好吧
All right. Fine.
大概一小时内在熊猫海岸酒店
There's an energy conference
有个能源会议
At the Panda Bay Hotel in about an hour.
他会去那儿的
He'll be there.
我说的是真话
That's the truth.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不知道该怎么去想
I don't know what to think.
快走  快快快
Go. Go, go go.
去找到他
Go find him.
我来看着她  去吧
I got her. Go.
如果她惹什么麻烦的话
If she gives you any trouble...
我知道
I know.
去吧
Just...go.
你超额完成了任务  巴格韦尔
You have surpassed expectations, Bagwell.
你不只会收集情报
You're much more than an informant.
我是多面手
I multitask.
很好  如果事情进展顺利
Hmm. Well, if things go as well as expected here,
你会按照约定得到奖赏
You'll be rewarded accordingly.
做公司的特别联络员吗
As a special liaison to the company?
没错
Yes.
要承担什么任务呢
What exactly does that entail?
那要你自己决定了
Well, that would be up to you.
通常公司的探员会选择自己的生涯规划
Most company operatives choose their own career path,
但是我不知道有什么适合你的
Though I can't say what would suit you.
来自阿拉巴马的强奸犯都会做什么啊
What do sexual predators from Alabama typically do,
除了表像上的
Uh, aside from the obvious?
那都是以前的事了  将军
Those days are behind me, general.
在教育上的缺陷
What I lack in formal education,
我能以天生的才能和好奇心
I more than make up for in
加倍弥补
Natural skills and curiosity.
还有  我的忠心永无止境
And as you've seen, my loyalty knows no bounds.
那你肯定会轻松
Then you shouldn't have any difficulty
通过最后考核
Passing your final exam.
你肯定不希望 有人暗算你
Now, you didn't expect that  a few phone calls on the sly
让你一辈子遭受牢狱之灾  是吧
would set you up for life, did you?
不想 先生
No, sir.
我可以做任何事
I'm ready for anything.
很好  那这件事就交给你了
Good. Then prepare for this.
布鲁斯拿到"锡拉"回来之后
When Burrows brings Scylla back to us,
我带着锡拉安全地飞回洛杉矶
I will fly it safely back to Los Angeles,
而你要送他上西天
And you will be the one to put a bullet in his brain.
莎拉
Sara?
里面怎么了
What's going on in there?
莎拉
Sara?
你要干什么
What do you want?
求你了  把门开着
Oh, please, keep that open.
为什么  想要 对我横加指责  妄加评价吗
Why? So you can Lob more accusations and assumptions out at me?
我没有
I haven't made any.
林肯是领养的
Lincoln is adopted.
还有  你怀孕了 你不否认  是吧
And you're pregnant. You don't deny it, do you?
你应该告诉他
You should tell him.
即使是现在  他也会很高兴的
He'd be happy, even under the circumstances.
这不关你的事
It really isn't any of your business.
对不起
I'm sorry.
有的时候  姻亲之间
Sometimes in-laws
也会冷血无情  但是...
Overstep their bounds, but...
真正到了紧要关头
You know, when it comes right down to it,
我和任何母亲都一样  所以...
I am the only mother any of you will ever have, so...
你不该这么早就下定结论的
You shouldn't throw that away so easily.
是啊  我从你身上学到
Yeah, you know, the only thing I get from you
一个好例子  千万别做你这样的母亲
Is a great example of the mother I don't want to be.
莎拉
Sara?
我们没必要搞成这样
It doesn't have to be like this.
有必要
Yeah, it does.
你早就决定好了
That was your decision a long time ago.
我能再给你 一点建议吗
Sara, Can I just give you One piece of advice?
千万别酗酒
Stay out of the bars.
说的好
That's good advice.
我在嗜酒者互诫协会里有些朋友 都是酒鬼
I have friends in AA. They're only alcoholics.
难以想象你要戒酒
I can only imagine what it's like for you,
有多难
Trying to stay off the smack.
是吗啡
It's morphine.
医用吗啡
Hospital-grade morphine.
克里斯蒂娜・斯科菲尔德今晚不会离开迈阿密了
Christina Scofield will not be leaving Miami tonight.
我要监视这里和亚特兰大
I want eyes at every airport and gas station
所有的机场和加油站
Between here and Atlanta.
我还要所有
And I want the names of everyone
出席会议的人员名单
attending that conference.
我就知道你会问这个问题
I thought you might be asking that question,
所以我打电话到宾馆的前台
So I called the front desk of the hotel.
说我是报社来的
Said I was from the newspaper.
请原谅某些拼写错误
Excuse the spelling.
这些都是科学家
These are all scientists.
我早告诉过你
I told you.
那些是演讲者
Those are the speakers.
下面这些名字是"特别嘉宾"
The names below are "special guests."
很像是世界各地的商业大亨
Sounded like bigwigs from all over the world.
福利德里克  克拉都
"Frederich, Carlotto,
琳娜特  班...
Linarte, Ban..."
班纳吉
"Banerjee"?
-纳文・班纳吉  -他是谁
- Naveen Banerjee?  - Who is that?
南都・班纳吉首相的儿子
The son of prime minister Nandu Banerjee.
众所周知  他对太阳能武器技术有兴趣
He has a known interest in solar weapons technology.
今天一切都要做个了断
This will all be over by the end of the day.
快点  林肯  你在哪呢
Come on, Linc, where are you?
我是林肯
It's Linc.
请留言
You know what to do.
林肯  是我 方便的时候给我打电话
Linc, it's me. Call me when you can.
我得跟你谈谈
We got to talk.
马宏
Mahone!
这边
This way!
克里斯蒂娜
Christina.
别动
Don't move.
否则我把你们母子俩都杀了
Or I'll kill you both.
他在哪
Where is he?
他去哪了
Where did he go?
这边
There.
-他在哪  -那儿  就在那边
- Where is he? - Right there, right there.
-林肯  停下  -为什么
- Lincoln, stop! - Why?
等等
Wait, wait.
就是这家宾馆
That's the hotel.
能源大会
The energy conference.
没错  就在今天
That's right-- it's today.
那辆银色的货车
The silver van.
租的那辆
The rental van.
他们把我们引来的
They want us here.
要出事了
Something's up.
这他妈是怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
东尼
Downey.
这是逃跑用的
It's for a getaway.
林肯  别去
Lincoln, no!
你在哪
Where are you?
在跑
Running.
布鲁斯在追我  你还好吧
Burrows is on my ass. Are you okay?
我还担心你逃不出来呢
I was worried you didn't get away.
这件事可以去见鬼了
This whole thing could go to hell.
我没事
I'm fine.
正是时候
I'm right on time.
待会见
See you soon.
跪下
Down.
这才像话
Good girl.
他不会原谅你这么做的
He'll never forgive you for this,
他哥哥也不会
And neither will his brother.
这些事很快就会变成过眼云烟的
Soon, this will all be behind us.
或许哪天我能看到我的孙子呢
Maybe I can meet my grandson one day.
喂
Nomaash Kaar.
对不起  纳文
My apologies, Naveen.
你去哪了
Where have you been?
别人告诉我  你会打来的
I was told that you would call.
因为晚上的安排拖了一会
I got hung up on a few details for this evening.
你和东尼谈过了吗
You spoke with Downey?
这很难让我放心
It did very little to reassure me.
我要跟圣丁斯奇教授通话
I need to speak to Dr. Sandinsky.
你没听说吗
Oh, you haven't heard?
圣丁斯奇教授家里有急事
Dr. Sandinsky had a family emergency.
他妻子出了严重的事故
His wife was in a terrible accident.
早上我跟他通过话了
I spoke with him this morning.
他下午会坐私人飞机赶来
He took a private jet out this afternoon.
现在做决定已经太迟了
It's very late to be making these decisions now.
不过你好不容易做出决定
Yes, but you've come all this way.
你准备好演讲了
You are prepared to give your speech,
对吧
Aren't you?
好吧
Fine.
不过先申明
But in light of the fact
没有教授在场我不会演讲
That I did not speak with the doctor,
我要修改协议
I'll amend my offer.
先是探索性研究资金100万
$1 million in exploratory research.
剩余部分下周到账
The rest will follow in the weeks to come.
纳文  你真大方
That's very generous, Naveen.
历史会记住你做出的贡献
History will thank you.
你的祖国会感谢你
Your country will thank you.
再见
See you soon.
各位注意
May I have your attention, please?
我们就要开始了
We're about to begin.
谢谢大家  欢迎来到迈阿密海滩
Thank you. Welcome to Miami beach.
感谢大家参加这方面的
And thank you for attending the first
首届全球性会议
Global conference of its kind,
精英们将共同探讨能源未来
Where great minds will meet to explore our energy future.
发掘新能源的重要性
The importance of finding new ways
不容低估
To power our world should not be underestimated.
车子还在运转
It's running.
他们以林肯的名义租的
They rented this in Linc's name.
看这个
Look at this.
是我们的护照
These passports. It's us.
这是陷阱
It's a setup.
-为什么  -这是陷阱
- For what?  - It's a setup!
谢谢
Thank you.
5点了
5 o'clock.
如果五分钟内布鲁斯再不来电话
If Burrows doesn't call in the next five minutes
你去市中心
You're going downtown.
将军  你看看这个
General, you should see this.
在迈阿密
In the city of Miami.
今天  熊猫海湾酒店召开会议
Today, the venue will be the Panda Bay Hotel,
鉴于有重要客人出席  保安措施严密
Where security it high in light of the important guests.
其中包括纳文・班纳吉
This includes Naveen Banerjee,
南都・班纳吉首相的儿子
Son of prime minister Nandu Banerjee,
他将进行主旨发言
Who is scheduled to be the event's keynote speaker.
班纳吉脆弱的政治地位
Banerjee's fragile political position
可能在世界舞台上受到批评
May leave him vulnerable to criticism on the world stage.
他对于环境政策的前景
He has aggressively sought to place his ideas...
克里斯蒂娜的计划
Christina's plan.
是从"锡拉"里获利
What she needed to profit from Scylla.
全球范围会产生多米诺效应
An incident that'll domino into global warfare.
克兰兹
Krantz.
你出局了
You're out.
一切都结束了
It's over now.
不
No!
导致了几个党派关系的紧张
Has caused some tension between several factions.
目前  美国决策制定者已经解决
So far, U.S. policymakers have resolved...
你来
You do it.
杀了他
Do it!
你需要通行证
You need a pass!
目前
At this point in our history,
太阳能的利用只占了
Solar power accounts for less than one-tenth of
全部能源中的千分之一不到
One percent of the total power generated in our world.
在接下来的十年里
And in the next ten years, that number
这个比例将增长到百分之十
Should increase to ten percent,
不过这还不够
But it's still not enough.
我们必须继续寻找方法
We must strive to seek new alternatives
才能打破对石油的依赖
So that we can break this cycle of oil dependence.
这少不了大家的帮助
We cannot do that without your help.
所以今天大家相聚在此
So that's why we are here today.
探索新能源的未来
To explore our new energy future
并展望明天
And envision a new tomorrow.
我们第一位嘉宾是作家亦是企业家
Now, our first guest is an author and an entrepreneur.
他的继承权世界闻名
As well as having a notable heritage,
并对全世界听众进行过演讲
He has spoken to audiences across the world.
大家欢迎  纳文・班纳吉
Please welcome, Naveen Banerjee.
谢谢
Thank you, thank you.
大家晚上好
Good evening, my friends.
今天  我很荣幸能和大家相聚在
It is my pleasure to be here with you today
这个美丽的阳光城市
In this beautiful city of sunlight.
我发现整个美国
Throughout the United States,
对于改变我们的能源
I find there to be great interest
有着很大的兴趣
In the changing way that we all power our world.
我提案过很多次
Many times I have been approached...
不要
No!
关于重复改造车轮的提议
With a proposal to reinvent the wheel.
新能源
New resources...
迈克
Michael!
林肯
Linc!
我们快离开这
We've got to go.
整件事情都是她一手策划的
She set the whole thing up.
你拿到了吗
Do you have it?
在这
Right here.
怎么样
How'd it go?
货车和护照都在那
The van was there with the passports.
我刚跟银行里的联系人通了电话
I just got off the phone with our contact at the bank.
布鲁斯要拿箱子的镜头
And they've got clean video of
被清晰地拍下来了
Burrows trying to access the box.
他一定在宾馆房间里翻箱倒柜
He must have trashed the hotel room.
到处都有他的指纹
His hands were all over the shells.
你看到迈克了吗
You see Michael?
我出来的时候他还在那
He was there on my way out.
林肯又要从头来过了
Lincoln's right back where he started.
这对迈克的确不太好
But really it's too bad about Micheal.
我了解你
I know you, uh...
闭嘴  快开车
Shut up and drive.